HENRIQUE FREITAS SOUZA

UI/UX DESIGNER

PROFILE

Phone +55 011 95435-5406

E-mail henrique@henriquefreitas.com.br

Portfolio henriquefreitas.com.br

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/henriquefreitassouza

Address Taboão da Serra, SP, Brazil

PITCH

I'm a UX designer who wrote many lines of code and worked at Fortune 100 companies. I love crafting new things, can't live without playing the guitar and I'm a tech geek. My dream is to see IoT everywhere to build experiences for all things.

EXPERIENCE

Conversion Chef | UI/UX Designer 2016 - Now

I create and test hypotheses based on data collected through the CRO process, perform A/B tests and heuristic analysis, design information architectures and redesign websites.

Learned the fundamentals of CRO

Nestlé | Project Manager 2014 - 2015

Managed infrastructure projects and represented Brazil as cloud solutions coordinator. Implemented and managed the cloud security process; managed CAPEX execution.

- · 3 projects delivered
- 15 cloud solutions security controls applied

Addbiz | Full Stack Developer 2010 - 2013

Designed and created UIs and graphic assets for hotsites, banners and e-mail marketing campaigns for an e-commerce. Developed hotsites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, PHP, MySQL and SQL Server.

- Learned much about many modern technologies
- Deployed hotsites for an e-commerce with 200,000+ users/month

EDUCATION

Designer (Hipster) | Gama Academy

2016

5 weeks course immersed in the startup ecossystem along with successfull CEOs and designers to learn the required soft and hard skills to work at startups.

- One of the 100 selected over 5412 candidates
- · 3rd in the rank of best design students

Information Systems | FIAP 2012 - 2015
Bachelor's degree.